

DAMJAN KOLEVSKI damjan.kolevski@gmail.com damjankol.github.io/portfolio

Product Design Engineer based in Prague

with a bachelor's degree of Industrial Design in Mechanical Engineering, and five years of work experience in that field, followed by an academy of UX Design, and over two years of work experience on that position.

His strongest competences are: Research, Prototyping, Programming, New product development, CAD, Mechanical Engineering, Project management, Graphic Design.

Industries he experiences: IT, Healthcare, Smart Manufacturing, Sport, Hospitality.

Personally, he is described as: committed, honest, reliable, enthusiastic, creative, details-oriented, communicative, adaptable, patient, tolerant.

DIGITAL COMPETENCE

- Adobe XD, Figma, InVision, Miro (Information Architecture, Wireframes, Prototypes)
- Photoshop, Illustrator (Graphic Design)
- HTML, CSS, JS, Angular, SQL (Programming)
- Azure DevOps, GitLab (Agile developing)
- Google Looker Studio (Data visualization)
- Solidworks, AutoCAD (3D assembly modelling, 2D tech. drawing)
- ProCast, Matlab, Adams (Dynamic simulations)
- 3ds MAX (Animation)

WORK EXPERIENCE

UX & Frontend Developer

OG Soft, Industry: IT, Mobile App Mar. 2023 - present, Usti nad Orlici

- UI Design (following Material 3 design system)
- Frontend programming (in Angular)
- Working in Agile environment (with GitLab)

UX Designer

TRIGAMA INT., Industry: IT, Mobile App, Wellness Jan. 2022 - Dec. 2022, Prague

- User Flows, User Interfaces (prototyping with Figma)
- User Interviews, User Tests (with Loop11)
- Working in Agile environment (with Azure DevOps)

UX Design Engineer

ATS GLOBAL, Industry: IT, SaaS, Industry 4.0 Apr. 2021 - Feb. 2022, Skopje

- User Researching, User Tests (with Userlytics)
- Mapping User Flows (with Miro)
- Designing Wireframes (with InVision)
- Designing Prototypes (with Figma)
- Implementing Web Accessibility (WCAG 2.0)
- Planning a development of Design System
- Working in Agile environment (with Azure DevOps)

R&D / CAD Mechanical Engineer

CRANFIELD FOUNDRY, Industry: Foundry Jan. 2019 - Sep. 2020, Probishtip

Development Engineer

CASTINVEST, Industry: Foundry Feb. 2018 - Oct. 2018, Skopje

Business Developer

REGEMAT 3D, Industry: Healthcare Aug. 2017 - Jan. 2018, Granada

Assistant to CEO

KOPLAST, Industry: Plastic Mar. 2015 - Jul. 2017, Skopje

Graphic Designer & Events Organizer

Macedonian Canoe Federation, Industry: Sport Mar. 2014 - present (part-time), Skopje

EDUCATION

BRAINSTER Academy of UX/UI Design

Jul. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Pre-program/Graphic Design (Photoshop, Illustrator)
- Fundamentals of UX/UI Design
- Tools: AdobeXD, Figma, InVision (Information Architecture, Wireframes, Prototypes)
- Design Systems, Responsive Design
- Front End Programming (HTML, CSS, JS)
- Storytelling, Pitching

MOTIVA Management Training

Feb. 2013 - Mar. 2013

Communication Skills; Developing and Managing Effective Teams; Entrepreneurship, Developing SMEs, Writing Business Plan; Financial Mgmt.; Leadership and Business Negotiation; Strategic Mgmt. and Business Ethics; Export Marketing; Presentation Skills; Change Mgmt.; Human Resources Mgmt.; Quality Mgmt.

University Ss. Cyril & Methodius in Skopje, Bachelor of Mech. Engineering in Industrial Design

Sep. 2011 - Jan. 2015

- Mechanical Engineering,
- New Product Development,
- 3D assembly modelling & 2D technical drawing (Solidworks, AutoCAD, MAYA, CATIA),
- Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing, Design for Manufacturability, Material Properties
- Graphic Design (Photoshop),
- Dynamic Simulation (Matlab, Adams),
- Animation (3ds MAX),
- Web Design/HTML/CSS (Dreamweaver)

Vocational Courses

- IBM: Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner (August 2021)
- IDF: User Research Methods and Best Practices (July 2021)
- IDF: Conducting Usability Testing (June 2021)

PERSONAL INFORMATION

- age: Millennial
- languages: English (fluent), Spanish (intermediate), French (beginner), Macedonian (mother tongue) Bulgarian (fluent), Croatian (fluent), Serbian (fluent).
- driver's license: B category (active driver)
- hobbies: Painting, Photography, Architecture, Folklore, Ecology, Humanitarian Volunteering, Tennis, Skiing, Volleyball, Hiking, White-water kayaking, Karate, Scouting, Dancing, Ice-skating, Table-tennis, Billiard, Ultimate Frisbee, Playing Piano, Flute...